<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-09T02:10:26+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Galaxy Australia</title><subtitle>The Australian Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Australia moves to new hardware</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/08/07/galaxy-australia-to-new-hardware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Australia moves to new hardware" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/08/07/galaxy-australia-to-new-hardware</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/08/07/galaxy-australia-to-new-hardware/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Australia moves to the new QRIS cloud stage 5 hardware&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This morning after a planned outage, the Galaxy Australia main queue was moved from it’s original home on QRIS cloud to their shiny new hardware! The stage 5 hardware is faster, better connected and much more flexible. This will help Galaxy Australia be more responsive to it’s users as we are now able to launch bigger jobs and have them run faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Galaxy Australia’s home, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://qriscloud.org.au&quot;&gt;QRIScloud website&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ardc.org.au&quot;&gt;ARDC&lt;/a&gt; refresh of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ardc.edu.au/collaborations/strategic-activities/storage-and-compute/research-cloud-request-for-proposals/&quot;&gt; NeCTAR Australian Research Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Galaxy Australia moves to the new QRIS cloud stage 5 hardware This morning after a planned outage, the Galaxy Australia main queue was moved from it’s original home on QRIS cloud to their shiny new hardware! The stage 5 hardware is faster, better connected and much more flexible. This will help Galaxy Australia be more responsive to it’s users as we are now able to launch bigger jobs and have them run faster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Australia upgraded to Galaxy version 19.05</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/25/galaxy-australia-to-galaxy-version-19-05/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Australia upgraded to Galaxy version 19.05" /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/25/galaxy-australia-to-galaxy-version-19-05</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/25/galaxy-australia-to-galaxy-version-19-05/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Australia has been upgraded to the latest Galaxy release. Version 19.05.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This morning after a brief planned outage, Galaxy Australia was upgraded to the latest version of Galaxy. You will notice some changes straight away - The colour scheme is different and the look and feel has altered. Everything else is the same however!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tool favourites! You can now tag tools that you use all the time and create your own “mini tool list”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improvements to History import/export.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A data selection dialog within tool forms to make it easier to select the data the tool is to run on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.galaxyproject.org/en/release_19.05/releases/19.05_announce_user.html&quot;&gt;user release notes&lt;/a&gt; for additional information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.galaxyproject.org/en/release_19.05/releases/19.05_announce.html&quot;&gt;full release notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Galaxy Australia has been upgraded to the latest Galaxy release. Version 19.05. This morning after a brief planned outage, Galaxy Australia was upgraded to the latest version of Galaxy. You will notice some changes straight away - The colour scheme is different and the look and feel has altered. Everything else is the same however!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Australia wins three Queensland iAwards</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/07/galaxy-australia-wins-three-queensland-iawards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Australia wins three Queensland iAwards" /><published>2019-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/07/galaxy-australia-wins-three-queensland-iawards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/06/07/galaxy-australia-wins-three-queensland-iawards/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 June 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Australia won three trophies at the Australian Information Industry Association’s (AIIA) Queensland state iAwards on Tuesday, 4 June, including the top prize, the Queensland Premier’s iAward for Public Sector Innovation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hon. Mick de Brenni, Queensland’s Minister for Digital Technology, presented Galaxy Australia with the Queensland Premier’s iAward at a gala event at the Rydges hotel, South Bank, Brisbane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it comes to being proud of fellow Queenslanders, it’s hard to look past an initiative that allows scientists to identify resolutions to genetic conditions that cause terminal cancer and debilitating disease,” said Mr de Brenni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To put it simply, this application could find the next cure for cancer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia also won &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aiia.com.au/iawards/about/2019-winners-and-merit-recipients?utm_source=2019+iAwards+Entrants&amp;amp;utm_campaign=7cc7851b56-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2017_06_08_COPY_01&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_term=0_3bea717129-7cc7851b56-329590441&quot;&gt;iAwards&lt;/a&gt; in the Infrastructure and Platforms Innovation of the Year, and Community Service Markets categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AIIA iAwards is the nation’s leading awards program that helps to recognise, celebrate and elevate Australian digital innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/galaxy-iaward-qld.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;galaxy-iaward-qld.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;L–R: Dr Dominique Gorse (QFAB), Derek Benson (RCC), Dr Gareth Price (QFAB), Nick Rhodes (QFAB)) and Dr Phil Gurney (QCIF) with the three Queensland iAwards won by the Galaxy Australia team. (Photo: Anne Bernard.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia is a free, Web-accessible platform to enable genetic scientists across the globe to test, evaluate and peer review their work, making the next cure for chronic disease within reach of anyone with the dedication and skills to look for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qcif.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Queensland Cyber Infrastructure Foundation (QCIF)&lt;/a&gt; and its bioinformatics arm &lt;a href=&quot;https://qfab.org/&quot;&gt;Queensland Facility for Advanced Bioinformatics (QFAB)&lt;/a&gt;, together with the University of Melbourne’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournebioinformatics.org.au/&quot;&gt;Melbourne Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt;, and the University of Queensland’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rcc.uq.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Research Computing Centre (RCC)&lt;/a&gt; jointly built and operate Galaxy Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia Service Manager Dr Gareth Price is very proud that his team’s work has been recognised with not just one, but three iAwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Personally, I was humbled by the calibre of entrants. We are proud to be honoured with these awards that reflect our contribution to Australian research by linking researchers and their data to national compute power and the analytical tools required to maximise research value,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Galaxy Australia exists to benefit its users — it helps life sciences researchers and clinicians analyse data without having to train in data science. The outcomes from this are massive: Galaxy Australia helps research groups better understand cancer and infectious diseases, and enables collaboration nationally and internationally.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melbourne University molecular biologist and computer scientist Associate Professor Andrew Lonie was always convinced of Galaxy’s potential when the project started in 2011. “It is now a mature platform for both analysing complex data and teaching the new generation of biologists how to do this new kind of research. We’re all very proud to celebrate these awards”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia is jointly supported by the Australian Research Data Commons (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ardc.edu.au/&quot;&gt;ARDC&lt;/a&gt;), the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournebioinformatics.org.au/project/aust-bioinformatics-commons/&quot;&gt;Australian Bioinformatics Commons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.embl-abr.org.au/&quot;&gt;EMBL Australia Bioinformatics Resource&lt;/a&gt;, with funding from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bioplatforms.com/&quot;&gt;Bioplatforms Australia&lt;/a&gt; as part of the federal Government’s 12-year commitment to the National Collaborative Research Infrastructure Strategy (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.education.gov.au/national-collaborative-research-infrastructure-strategy-ncris&quot;&gt;NCRIS&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Queensland iAward winner, Galaxy Australia will be a finalist in the national iAwards on Thursday, 29 August in Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AIIA CEO Ron Gauci said: “Each year the AIIA iAwards shine a light on the exceptional achievements of those at the forefront of Australian innovation, and the projects shaping our modern economy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National iAward winners will represent Australia at the Asia Pacific ICT Alliance (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apicta.org/&quot;&gt;APICTA&lt;/a&gt;) Awards, dubbed the “Oscars of the ICT arena”, in HaLong, Vietnam, 18–23 November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For further media information contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shannon Lindsay, QCIF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ph: 0420 524 392&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shannon.lindsay@qcif.edu.au&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helen van de Pol, Melbourne Bioinformatics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ph: 0448 920 235&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;helen.vandepol@unimelb.edu.au&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABOUT US:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QCIF&lt;/strong&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qcif.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Queensland Cyber Infrastructure Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (QCIF) provides the high-performance services, infrastructure and expertise to enable excellence in data-centric, collaborative research and its application. QCIF operates with its members and partners delivering high-value services to researchers throughout Queensland and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melbourne Bioinformatics, University of Melbourne&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournebioinformatics.org.au/&quot;&gt;Melbourne Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt; provides bioinformatics support for all researchers and students in Melbourne’s biomedical and biosciences precinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Computing Centre, University of Queensland&lt;/strong&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://rcc.uq.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Research Computing Centre&lt;/a&gt; (RCC) provides coordinated management and support of The University of Queensland’s sustained and substantial investment in eResearch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bioplatforms Australia&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bioplatforms.com/&quot;&gt;Bioplatforms Australia&lt;/a&gt; enables Australian life science research by investing in state-of-the-art infrastructure and associated expertise in the specialist fields of genomics, proteomics, metabolomics and bioinformatics. We create open-data initiatives through collaborative research projects, which build critical ‘omic datasets that support scientific challenges of national importance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="info" /><summary type="html">7 June 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Text processing tools disabled</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/05/02/text-processing-tools-disabled/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Text processing tools disabled" /><published>2019-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/05/02/text-processing-tools-disabled</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/05/02/text-processing-tools-disabled/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text processing tools&lt;/strong&gt; have been disabled due to security concerns with one of it’s dependencies. We will re-enable these tools once the security patch has been developed and applied.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Text processing tools have been disabled due to security concerns with one of it’s dependencies. We will re-enable these tools once the security patch has been developed and applied.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Australia upgraded to Galaxy version 19.01</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/04/09/galaxy-version-upgraded-to-19-01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Australia upgraded to Galaxy version 19.01" /><published>2019-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/04/09/galaxy-version-upgraded-to-19-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/04/09/galaxy-version-upgraded-to-19-01/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Australia has been upgraded to the latest Galaxy release. Version 19.01.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This morning after a brief planned outage, Galaxy Australia was upgraded to the latest version of Galaxy. You will notice some changes straight away - The colour scheme is different and the look and feel has altered. Everything else is the same however!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release includes the revised UI style, addition of colourful tags, extensive workflow enhancements, and enhanced support for Singularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.galaxyproject.org/en/release_19.01/releases/19.01_announce.html&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for additional information.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Galaxy Australia has been upgraded to the latest Galaxy release. Version 19.01. This morning after a brief planned outage, Galaxy Australia was upgraded to the latest version of Galaxy. You will notice some changes straight away - The colour scheme is different and the look and feel has altered. Everything else is the same however!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resolved - Service Slow Down 20-22 March 2019.</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/25/emergency-downtime/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resolved - Service Slow Down 20-22 March 2019." /><published>2019-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/25/emergency-downtime</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/25/emergency-downtime/">&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that Galaxy Australia was slow to respond from the 20th - 22nd of March 2019 - This has been resolved. Upon investigation the slow down was caused by a live migration of some of the backend storage to a new faster platform. The migration is mostly completed and our normal excellent level of service was resumed on the 23rd March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank you for your patience during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia Admin Team.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">You may have noticed that Galaxy Australia was slow to respond from the 20th - 22nd of March 2019 - This has been resolved. Upon investigation the slow down was caused by a live migration of some of the backend storage to a new faster platform. The migration is mostly completed and our normal excellent level of service was resumed on the 23rd March.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New FTP upload URL</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/18/new-ftp-upload-url/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New FTP upload URL" /><published>2019-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/18/new-ftp-upload-url</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/18/new-ftp-upload-url/">&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia has recently changed the URL for FTP uploads. If you need to upload large files to Galaxy Australia, simply log in to the FTP server at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.usegalaxy.org.au/&quot;&gt;ftp://ftp.usegalaxy.org.au/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with your favourite FTP software using your &lt;strong&gt;Galaxy Australia&lt;/strong&gt; credentials. For help visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.org/ftp-upload/&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free FTP Client Software can be downloaded for your Operating System at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://filezilla-project.org/&quot;&gt;https://filezilla-project.org/&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyberduck.io/&quot;&gt;https://cyberduck.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Galaxy Australia has recently changed the URL for FTP uploads. If you need to upload large files to Galaxy Australia, simply log in to the FTP server at ftp://ftp.usegalaxy.org.au/ with your favourite FTP software using your Galaxy Australia credentials. For help visit the tutorial.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galactic News March 2019</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/14/galaxy-march-newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galactic News March 2019" /><published>2019-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/14/galaxy-march-newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/14/galaxy-march-newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galactic News March 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The March newsletter for the Galaxy project is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.org/news/2019-03-galaxy-update/&quot;&gt;https://galaxyproject.org/news/2019-03-galaxy-update/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;March Galactic News&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GCC 2019 Sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Galaxy Admins meetups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upcoming global training events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More publications citing Galaxy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training material updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="galaxy" /><summary type="html">Galactic News March 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Version 19.01 Released</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/06/Galaxy-version-19-01-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Version 19.01 Released" /><published>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/06/Galaxy-version-19-01-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/03/06/Galaxy-version-19-01-released/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Galaxy 19.01 has now been released!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This release includes the revised UI style, addition of colorful tags, extensive workflow enhancements, and enhanced support for Singularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.galaxyproject.org/en/release_19.01/releases/19.01_announce.html&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for additional information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Australia will be moving to this Galaxy version in the upcoming weeks. More information will be forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">Galaxy 19.01 has now been released! This release includes the revised UI style, addition of colorful tags, extensive workflow enhancements, and enhanced support for Singularity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New tools added: Heatmaps and VSearch</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/02/27/new-tools-added/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New tools added: Heatmaps and VSearch" /><published>2019-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/02/27/new-tools-added</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2019/02/27/new-tools-added/">&lt;p&gt;This week we have added a number of new tools to Galaxy Australia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New tools:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heatmap w ggplot&lt;/em&gt;: This tool will generate a clustered heatmap of your data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heatmap2&lt;/em&gt;: Employs the heatmap.2 function from the R gplots package and will generate a heatmap of your data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;chimera.vsearch&lt;/em&gt;: Part of the Mothur suite - find potential chimeric sequences using vsearch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated tools:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;VSearch suite&lt;/em&gt;: now at version 2.8.3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">This week we have added a number of new tools to Galaxy Australia</summary></entry></feed>