<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-05T13:57:15+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/</id><title type="html">Galaxy Australia</title><subtitle>The Australian Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Tools Added: Gemini Tools</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/05/new-tools-added-gemini-tools/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Tools Added: Gemini Tools" /><published>2018-12-05T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-12-05T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/05/new-tools-added-gemini-tools</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/05/new-tools-added-gemini-tools/">&lt;p&gt;We have added the Gemini Tools to Galaxy Australia. These tools are for doing integrative exploration of genetic variation and genome annotations. The documentation for these tools can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can find these tools under the &lt;strong&gt;Gemini Tools&lt;/strong&gt; section of the Galaxy Australia tool menu.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tool" /><summary type="html">We have added the Gemini Tools to Galaxy Australia. These tools are for doing integrative exploration of genetic variation and genome annotations. The documentation for these tools can be found here. You can find these tools under the Gemini Tools section of the Galaxy Australia tool menu.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nominate a training for the 2019 Galaxy Community Conference (GCC2019)</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/03/gcc-training-nomination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nominate a training for the 2019 Galaxy Community Conference (GCC2019)" /><published>2018-12-03T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-12-03T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/03/gcc-training-nomination</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/12/03/gcc-training-nomination/">&lt;p&gt;The 2019 Galaxy Community Conference (GCC2019) will be held in be held in Freiburg, Germany, 1-6 July. The training topics that are offered are determined by the community so &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1fBPjEmw7Td52rhBnC0SvflnQCD7Ue5IMJ9RkM0SjnYg/&quot;&gt;BY YOU&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">The 2019 Galaxy Community Conference (GCC2019) will be held in be held in Freiburg, Germany, 1-6 July. The training topics that are offered are determined by the community so BY YOU!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Automatic workflow testing</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/21/workflow-testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automatic workflow testing" /><published>2018-11-21T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/21/workflow-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/21/workflow-testing/">&lt;p&gt;We have started to test a few of our workflows automatically against &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu&quot;&gt;UseGalaxy.eu&lt;/a&gt;.
This will run all workflows monthly to ensure that the keep working and that our infrastructure works and scales well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contribute workflows to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usegalaxy-eu/workflow-testing&quot;&gt;testing repository&lt;/a&gt; or
propose us workflows via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usegalaxy-eu/workflow-testing/issues/new&quot;&gt;opening an issue&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively you can write us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@usegalaxy.eu&quot;&gt;contact@usegalaxy.eu&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like us to test these workflows on your server, just get in contact with us and we can do that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usegalaxy-eu/workflow-testing&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/workflow_testing.png&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;List of workflows under testing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">We have started to test a few of our workflows automatically against UseGalaxy.eu. This will run all workflows monthly to ensure that the keep working and that our infrastructure works and scales well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorial of the Month: “Reference-based RNA-Seq data analysis”, selected by Saskia Hiltemann</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/15/totm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorial of the Month: &quot;Reference-based RNA-Seq data analysis&quot;, selected by Saskia Hiltemann" /><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/15/totm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/11/15/totm/">&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy community is developing and maintaining a collection of tutorials that are designed to be interactive and are built around Galaxy: &lt;a href=&quot;https://training.galaxyproject.org&quot;&gt;https://training.galaxyproject.org&lt;/a&gt;. To help highlight our tutorials and the training effort of the community, a member of the community will select every month one tutorial and explains in the &lt;em&gt;Galactic Blog&lt;/em&gt; why they select this tutorial. This month, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.org/blog/2018-10-totm/2018-11-cotm-saskia-hiltemann&quot;&gt;Galaxy contributor of the Month!&lt;/a&gt;, Saskia Hilteman, selects and presents a tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/transcriptomics/tutorials/ref-based/tutorial.html&quot;&gt;“Reference-based RNA-Seq data analysis”&lt;/a&gt;, from the topic &lt;a href=&quot;http://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/transcriptomics&quot;&gt;“Transcriptomics”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">The Galaxy community is developing and maintaining a collection of tutorials that are designed to be interactive and are built around Galaxy: https://training.galaxyproject.org. To help highlight our tutorials and the training effort of the community, a member of the community will select every month one tutorial and explains in the Galactic Blog why they select this tutorial. This month, the Galaxy contributor of the Month!, Saskia Hilteman, selects and presents a tutorial: “Reference-based RNA-Seq data analysis”, from the topic “Transcriptomics”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Initial release of `gxadmin` tool</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/10/08/gxadmin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Initial release of `gxadmin` tool" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/10/08/gxadmin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/10/08/gxadmin/">&lt;p&gt;The good folks over at Galaxy Europe have developed a cool bit of code to help out Galaxy systems administrators. It’s called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gxadmin&lt;/code&gt;, it’s available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usegalaxy-eu/gxadmin&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
and includes many small SQL queries that administrators run every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Galaxy administrator, you can use it to do things like viewing the queue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gxadmin query queue
                            tool_id                                |  state  | count
-------------------------------------------------------------------+---------+-------
 toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/unicycler/unicycler/0.4.6.0      | queued  |     9
 toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/dexseq/dexseq_count/1.24.0.0     | running |     7
 toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/nml/spades/spades/1.2                | queued  |     6
 ebi_sra_main                                                      | running |     6
 toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/trinity/trinity/2.8.3            | queued  |     5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;amongst many more queries. We hope that other administrators will find this
utility useful and can contribute queries that they run often.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">The good folks over at Galaxy Europe have developed a cool bit of code to help out Galaxy systems administrators. It’s called gxadmin, it’s available on GitHub and includes many small SQL queries that administrators run every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GCCBOSC</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/18/gccbosc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GCCBOSC" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/18/gccbosc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/18/gccbosc/">&lt;p&gt;From 24th of June to 2nd of July the Galaxy Community Conference (GCC) and Bioinformatics Open Source Conference 2018 (BOSC) were meeting together in Portland, Oregon, United States. There was be two days of training, a two day meeting, and four days of intense collaboration.  The meeting featured joint &amp;amp; parallel sessions, shared keynotes, poster &amp;amp; demo sessions, birds-of-a-feather, and social events.  Simon and Derek were there and represented the Galaxy Australia team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/134305289@N03/albums/72157695693844792&quot; title=&quot;GCCBOSC&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/846/43248513092_b4efcaa655_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; alt=&quot;GCCBOSC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event started with 2 days of training. Bérénice, Joachim, and Björn trained there (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/DmxD/galaxy-101-a-gentle-introduction-to-using-galaxy&quot;&gt;Galaxy 101 - A gentle introduction to using Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/Drp9/bioinformatics-training-and-education-with-the-galaxy-training-network&quot;&gt;Bioinformatics Training and Education with the Galaxy Training Network&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/Dn3G/conda-and-containers&quot;&gt;Conda and Containers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/DnAc/galaxy-interactive-environments&quot;&gt;Galaxy Interactive Environments&lt;/a&gt;) but also participated on trainings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the two day conference started with several interesting keynotes (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/EQF7/opening-keynote-tracy-k-teal-democratizing-data&quot;&gt;Tracy K Teal on Democratization of data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/EQ3d/keynote-fernando-perez-sustainable-development-of-scientific-open-source-tools-a-view-from-jupyter&quot;&gt;Fernando Pérez on Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/EQFC/closing-keynote-confound-it-reproducible-biology-from-omics-data-analysis&quot;&gt;Lucia Peixoto on reproducibility of biology&lt;/a&gt;) and parallel tracks of talks and posters for GCC and BOSC. Joachim presented &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/EYNG/galaxy-hicexplorer-hicexplorer-deeptools3-and-pygenometracks&quot;&gt;Galaxy HiCExplorer&lt;/a&gt; and Bérénice a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gccbosc2018.sched.com/event/EYF1/a-fruitful-year-for-the-galaxy-training-materials&quot;&gt;report of the Galaxy Training material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;embed src=&quot;https://api.accusoft.com/v1/viewer/?key=aIAHEk1WtoJas0JtfMsvfRTwAP3ApQikUG4NnwM3RzGuKnHIty0UftIkfzzFE6XS&amp;amp;viewertype=html5&amp;amp;document=https://d1hiluowqo0t4b.cloudfront.net/posters/compressed/f1000research-211135.pdf&amp;amp;viewerHeight=550&amp;amp;viewerWidth=100%&amp;amp;upperToolbarColor=373e46&amp;amp;lowerToolbarColor=eeeeee&amp;amp;bottomToolbarColor=373e46&amp;amp;backgroundColor=f7f6f5&amp;amp;fontColor=ffffff&amp;amp;buttonColor=black&amp;amp;hidden=selectText,download,panTool,magnifyTool,rotateDocument,rotatePage,fullScreen,print,pageInfo,redact,esign&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; height=&quot;450px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these 4 days the CollaborationFest started - and it was really productive! Many discussions, new contributions and contributors, improvement of our training materials, new Bioconda packages and new BioContainer and so much more that will find its way into the next Galaxy releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conference was really intense in so many ways! To get the feeling, you can check out Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/gccbosc?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;src=hash&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;#GCCBOSC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">From 24th of June to 2nd of July the Galaxy Community Conference (GCC) and Bioinformatics Open Source Conference 2018 (BOSC) were meeting together in Portland, Oregon, United States. There was be two days of training, a two day meeting, and four days of intense collaboration. The meeting featured joint &amp;amp; parallel sessions, shared keynotes, poster &amp;amp; demo sessions, birds-of-a-feather, and social events. Simon and Derek were there and represented the Galaxy Australia team!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bioconda: sustainable and comprehensive software distribution for the life sciences</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/04/Bioconda/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bioconda: sustainable and comprehensive software distribution for the life sciences" /><published>2018-07-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-07-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/04/Bioconda</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-au.github.io/posts/2018/07/04/Bioconda/">&lt;p&gt;3 years ago the Galaxy community evaluated mechanism to make software installation more robust and we joined
the Bioconda community, to fix the software deployment problem once and for all.
Today, we are happy to annouce that the Bioconda manuscript is now published in the latest
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41592-018-0046-7&quot;&gt;Nature Methods issue&lt;/a&gt; (public &lt;a href=&quot;https://rdcu.be/2kbI&quot;&gt;view&lt;/a&gt;).
usegalaxy.org.au and many other Galaxy instance are already powered by Bioconda and you might use it daily
without knowing :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/bioconda_nmeth.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;Stats from Bioconda&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bioinformatics software comes in a variety of programming languages and requires diverse installation methods.
This heterogeneity makes management of a software stack complicated, error-prone, and inordinately time-consuming.
Whereas software deployment has traditionally been handled by administrators, ensuring the reproducibility of
data analyses1,2,3 requires that the researcher be able to maintain full control of the software environment,
rapidly modify it without administrative privileges, and reproduce the same software stack on different machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conda package manager (https://conda.io) has become an increasingly popular means to overcome these challenges
for all major operating systems. Conda normalizes software installations across language ecosystems
by describing each software with a human readable ‘recipe’ that defines meta-information and dependencies,
as well as a simple ‘build script’ that performs the steps necessary to build and install the software.
Conda builds software packages in an isolated environment, transforming them into relocatable binaries.
Importantly, it obviates reliance on system-wide administration privileges by allowing users to generate
isolated software environments in which they can manage software versions by project, without generating
incompatibilities and side-effects (Supplementary Results). These environments support reproducibility,
as they can be rapidly exchanged via files that describe their installation state.
Conda is tightly integrated into popular solutions for reproducible data analysis such as Galaxy,
bcbio-nextgen (https://github.com/chapmanb/bcbio-nextgen), and Snakemake.
To further enhance reproducibility guarantees, Conda can be combined with container or virtual
machine-based approaches and archive facilities such as Zenodo (Supplementary Results).
Finally, although Conda provides many commonly used packages by default, it also allows users to
optionally include additional, community-managed repositories of packages (termed channels).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To unlock the benefits of Conda for the life sciences, we present the Bioconda project
(https://bioconda.github.io). The Bioconda project provides over 3,000 &lt;strong&gt;(Updated: 4000!!!)&lt;/strong&gt; Conda
software packages for Linux and macOS. Rapid turnaround times (Supplementary Results)
and extensive documentation (https://bioconda.github.io/contributing.html) have led to a growing community
of over 200 international scientists working in the project (Supplementary Results).
The project is led by a core team, which is complemented by interest groups for
particular language ecosystems. Unlimited (in time and space) storage for generated packages
is donated by Anaconda Inc. All other used infrastructure is free of charge. Bioconda provides
packages from various language ecosystems such as Python, R (CRAN and Bioconductor), Perl,
Haskell, Java, and C/C++ (Fig. 1a). Many of the packages have complex dependency structures
that require various manual steps for installation when not relying on a package manager like
Conda (Supplementary Results). With over 6.3 million downloads,
Bioconda has become a backbone of bioinformatics infrastructure that is used heavily
across all language ecosystems (Fig. 1b). It is complemented by the conda-forge
project (https://conda-forge.github.io), which hosts software not specifically related to the
biological sciences. This separation has proven beneficial, because the focused nature
of the Bioconda community allows for fast turnaround times and support when a user needs
to contribute packages or fix problems. Nevertheless, the two projects collaborate
closely, and the Bioconda team maintains over 500 packages hosted by conda-forge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">3 years ago the Galaxy community evaluated mechanism to make software installation more robust and we joined the Bioconda community, to fix the software deployment problem once and for all. Today, we are happy to annouce that the Bioconda manuscript is now published in the latest Nature Methods issue (public view). usegalaxy.org.au and many other Galaxy instance are already powered by Bioconda and you might use it daily without knowing :)</summary></entry></feed>